<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Jaigarage</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/categories/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Jaigarage</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>No UTF-8 Locale Fix</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/no-utf-fix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/no-utf-fix/</guid><description>Locales define the language, country, and character encoding settings for your system. UTF-8 is a variable-width character encoding that can represent every character in the Unicode character set, making it essential for displaying international characters and ensuring proper text handling in modern Linux environments.</description></item><item><title>Icon Themes</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/icon-themes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/icon-themes/</guid><description>Customizing the look and feel of your Linux desktop is one of its most appealing features. Icon themes and desktop themes can dramatically change your user interface, making it more aesthetically pleasing and personalized. This guide will walk you through installing and applying some popular icon and desktop themes, specifically focusing on the Papirus Icon Theme and Arc KDE Theme, to enhance your Linux experience.</description></item><item><title>Operating System</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/os/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/os/</guid><description>Choosing and installing an operating system is a fundamental step in setting up any computer. Linux, a powerful and open-source operating system, offers unparalleled flexibility, security, and a vast ecosystem of software. This guide will walk you through the process of installing a Linux-based operating system, covering how to select a distribution, create bootable installation media, and perform the initial setup.</description></item></channel></rss>