<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Jaigarage</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/topics/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Jaigarage</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/topics/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pass: The Unix Password Store</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/pass/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/pass/</guid><description>&lt;code&gt;pass&lt;/code&gt;, also known as the Unix password store, is a simple, command-line-driven password manager that follows the Unix philosophy. It stores passwords in GPG-encrypted files, organized in a simple directory tree, and can be easily synchronized using Git.</description></item><item><title>Pi-hole: Network-wide Ad Blocking</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/pihole/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/pihole/</guid><description>Pi-hole is a Linux network-level advertisement and Internet tracker blocking application which acts as a DNS sinkhole, and optionally a DHCP server, for a private network. It is designed to protect your devices from unwanted content like ads, trackers, and malicious websites across your entire network, improving privacy and browsing speed.</description></item><item><title>Btop</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/btop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/btop/</guid><description>&lt;code&gt;btop&lt;/code&gt; is a fast, modern, and fully customizable command-line resource monitor that displays usage and stats for processor, memory, disks, network, and processes. It&amp;rsquo;s a visually appealing and feature-rich alternative to traditional tools like &lt;code&gt;top&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;htop&lt;/code&gt;, offering an interactive interface and extensive configuration options.</description></item><item><title>Hugo CLI</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/hugo-cli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/hugo-cli/</guid><description>Auto-completion for command-line interface (CLI) tools significantly enhances productivity by reducing typing, minimizing errors, and making it easier to discover available commands and options. If you want auto-completion for Hugo commands in the terminal (CLI), you can enable shell completion for Bash.</description></item><item><title>No UTF-8 Locale Fix</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/no-utf-fix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/no-utf-fix/</guid><description>Locales define the language, country, and character encoding settings for your system. UTF-8 is a variable-width character encoding that can represent every character in the Unicode character set, making it essential for displaying international characters and ensuring proper text handling in modern Linux environments.</description></item><item><title>Browsers</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/browsers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/browsers/</guid><description>Web browsers are arguably the most essential applications on any computer, serving as our primary gateway to the internet. With a multitude of options available, choosing and installing the right browser for your needs is crucial. This guide will walk you through the installation process for two of the most popular web browsers on Linux: Google Chrome and Mozilla Firefox.</description></item><item><title>Icon Themes</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/icon-themes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/icon-themes/</guid><description>Customizing the look and feel of your Linux desktop is one of its most appealing features. Icon themes and desktop themes can dramatically change your user interface, making it more aesthetically pleasing and personalized. This guide will walk you through installing and applying some popular icon and desktop themes, specifically focusing on the Papirus Icon Theme and Arc KDE Theme, to enhance your Linux experience.</description></item><item><title>Operating System</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/os/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/os/</guid><description>Choosing and installing an operating system is a fundamental step in setting up any computer. Linux, a powerful and open-source operating system, offers unparalleled flexibility, security, and a vast ecosystem of software. This guide will walk you through the process of installing a Linux-based operating system, covering how to select a distribution, create bootable installation media, and perform the initial setup.</description></item><item><title>ADB CLI: Connect and Debug Android Devices</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/adb-cli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/adb-cli/</guid><description>Android Debug Bridge (ADB) is a versatile command-line tool that lets you communicate with an Android-powered device. ADB provides various device actions, such as installing and debugging apps, and it offers access to a Unix shell that you can use to run commands on a device.</description></item><item><title>Mobile Screencast: Android to OBS via RTMP &amp; IP Camera</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/mobile-screencast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/mobile-screencast/</guid><description>Mobile screencasting allows you to display your mobile device&amp;rsquo;s screen on another device, such as a computer, often for recording or live streaming. This is particularly useful for creating tutorials, showcasing mobile games, delivering presentations, or simply mirroring your phone&amp;rsquo;s display to a larger screen.</description></item><item><title>Sync Folders with Rsync</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/sync-folder/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/sync-folder/</guid><description>Rsync (remote synchronize) is a fast and versatile command-line utility for synchronizing files and directories between two locations. It&amp;rsquo;s widely used for backups, mirroring, and data migration due to its efficiency in transferring only the changed parts of files.</description></item><item><title>Gemini-CLI Setup in Linux</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/gemini-cli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/gemini-cli/</guid><description>This guide will walk you through setting up the Gemini CLI on a Linux system. The Gemini CLI is a powerful tool for interacting with Google&amp;rsquo;s Gemini models directly from your command line, enabling scripting, automation, and quick experimentation with AI models.</description></item></channel></rss>