<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configuration on Jaigarage</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/topics/configuration/</link><description>Recent content in Configuration on Jaigarage</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/topics/configuration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pi-hole: Network-wide Ad Blocking</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/pihole/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/pihole/</guid><description>Pi-hole is a Linux network-level advertisement and Internet tracker blocking application which acts as a DNS sinkhole, and optionally a DHCP server, for a private network. It is designed to protect your devices from unwanted content like ads, trackers, and malicious websites across your entire network, improving privacy and browsing speed.</description></item><item><title>Btop</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/btop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/btop/</guid><description>&lt;code&gt;btop&lt;/code&gt; is a fast, modern, and fully customizable command-line resource monitor that displays usage and stats for processor, memory, disks, network, and processes. It&amp;rsquo;s a visually appealing and feature-rich alternative to traditional tools like &lt;code&gt;top&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;htop&lt;/code&gt;, offering an interactive interface and extensive configuration options.</description></item><item><title>No UTF-8 Locale Fix</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/no-utf-fix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/no-utf-fix/</guid><description>Locales define the language, country, and character encoding settings for your system. UTF-8 is a variable-width character encoding that can represent every character in the Unicode character set, making it essential for displaying international characters and ensuring proper text handling in modern Linux environments.</description></item><item><title>Gemini-CLI Setup in Linux</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/gemini-cli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/gemini-cli/</guid><description>This guide will walk you through setting up the Gemini CLI on a Linux system. The Gemini CLI is a powerful tool for interacting with Google&amp;rsquo;s Gemini models directly from your command line, enabling scripting, automation, and quick experimentation with AI models.</description></item></channel></rss>