<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installation on Jaigarage</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/topics/installation/</link><description>Recent content in Installation on Jaigarage</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/topics/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Browsers</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/browsers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/browsers/</guid><description>Web browsers are arguably the most essential applications on any computer, serving as our primary gateway to the internet. With a multitude of options available, choosing and installing the right browser for your needs is crucial. This guide will walk you through the installation process for two of the most popular web browsers on Linux: Google Chrome and Mozilla Firefox.</description></item><item><title>Operating System</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/os/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/os/</guid><description>Choosing and installing an operating system is a fundamental step in setting up any computer. Linux, a powerful and open-source operating system, offers unparalleled flexibility, security, and a vast ecosystem of software. This guide will walk you through the process of installing a Linux-based operating system, covering how to select a distribution, create bootable installation media, and perform the initial setup.</description></item><item><title>Gemini-CLI Setup in Linux</title><link>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/gemini-cli/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jaigansa.github.io/jaigarage/posts/gemini-cli/</guid><description>This guide will walk you through setting up the Gemini CLI on a Linux system. The Gemini CLI is a powerful tool for interacting with Google&amp;rsquo;s Gemini models directly from your command line, enabling scripting, automation, and quick experimentation with AI models.</description></item></channel></rss>